# Matthew Bogard

≥ matthewkbogard@gmail.com

mbogard.com

(512) 961-9526

**Austin, TX 78704** 



Proficient Technologies

JavaScript

React.js, Redux & React Native

Node.js

HTML

**CSS** 

Express.js

iQuery

SQL

Docker

WordPress API & Pantheon

Testing Frameworks (Jest, AVA, & Cypress)

**Amazon Web Services** 

Terraform

Java, Spring Boot

Python

**PHP** 

## **SUMMARY**

Ambitious and knowledgeable full-stack software developer. Proficient in creating modern frontend applications, interacting with back-end APIs, and managing applications using cloud services and database scripts. I can confidently jump into a complicated existing code base, or build new sustainable apps that use intuitive logic. Embraces opportunities to collaborate and expand technical expertise.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Engineer, Red Ventures - Dec. 2018-Present

- Built business-critical applications from the ground up as well as created features and fixed bugs for existing applications
- Contributed to every stage of the development process—from the initial project management discussions of a new feature all the way to its final implementation in production
- Created and maintained many integral internal apps and tools for owned websites using JavaScript, specifically React and Node.js
- Established Amazon Web Services infrastructure for applications using Terraform code
- Improved APIs central to revenue, specifically APIs written in Java's Spring framework
- Managed a Content Management System for thousands of editorial articles using WordPress API as well as Python and Node.js scripts

#### Project Manager (Promotion), Texas Health & Human Services - Jan. 2018–Jun. 2018

 Managed projects related to programming Texas Medicare & Medicaid rates for the department of 150 employees

# Rate Analyst, Texas Health & Human Services - Jan. 2017-Jan. 2018

 Wrote, reviewed, and refined SPSS code used for calculating annual changes in Texas Medicare & Medicaid rates

# **EDUCATION**

Full-Stack Web Development Certification, The University of Texas at Austin Earned Certificate and Completed the Coding Bootcamp Program

Bachelor's Degree, The University of Texas at Austin - 2013-2016

Graduated with Bachelor of Arts in Government, Minor in Rhetoric and Writing Cumulative GPA: 3.5

## **SKILLS**

- Comprehensive team contributor, from helping Platform teams effectively run their cloud services to assisting QA teams automate their testing suites
- Knowledgeable manager of repositories with Git version control as well as a proficient user of powerful CLI tools, IDEs including all JetBrains products, and GUIs like Postman

# **VIEW MORE**

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-bogard/
- <a href="http://us-census-data.herokuapp.com/">http://us-census-data.herokuapp.com/</a>
   My open source tool for exploring American city data related to political party, race, income, and population
- https://mbogard.com/music/
  Page within my personal website mbogard.com that showcases original music
- https://medium.com/@mbogard/what-coding-bootcamps-dont-teachc71c3182f11

My Medium article teaching how to best use Docker in web app development